Chapter 38. Dusk.
By the main mist, Starbucks leaning against it.
My soul is more than matched. She's overmanned. And by a madman,
insufferable sting that sanity should ground arms on such a field. But he
drilled deep down and blasted all my reason out of me. I think I see his
impious end, but feel that I must help him to it. Will I n I the ineffable
thing has tied me to him. Toes me with a cable I have no knife to cut. Horrible
old man. Who's over him? He cries. I He would be a democrat to all above. Look
how he lords it over all below. Oh, I plainly see my miserable office to obey
rebelling and worse yet to hate with a touch of pity. For in his eyes I read
some lurid woe would shrivel me up had I it. Yet is there hope. Time and tide
flow wide. The hated whale has the round watery world to swim in as the small
goldfish has its glassy globe. His heaven insulting purpose God may wedge
aside. I would upheart were it not like lead. But my whole clock's run down. My
heart the all controlling weight I have no key to lift again. A burst of revalry
from the folks.
Oh God to sail with such a heathen crew that have small touch of human mothers
in them. Welped somewhere by the sharkish sea. The white whale is their demigorgon.
Hark the infernal orgies. That revalry is forward. Mark the unfaltering silence
aft. Me thinks it pictures life.
Foremost through the sparkling sea shoots the gay embattled bantering bow,
but only to drag dark Ahab after it where he broods within his sternward
cabin, build it over the dead water of the wake, and further on hunted by its wolfish gurglings.
The long howl thrills me through. Peace you revelers, and set the watch. Oh
life, it is an hour like this with soul beat down and held to knowledge as wild
untutoed things are forced to feed. Oh life, it is now that I do feel the
latent horror in thee. But it is not me that horrors out of me and with the soft
feeling of the human in me. Yet I will try to fight you, you grim phantom
futures. Stand by me. Hold me. Bind me.
Oh, you blessed influences.